Now our contract is
现在我们的合约已经
good as it is, it allows us to store a single favorite number.
很不错了，它允许我们存储单一一个喜欢的数字。
But what if we want to store a range of favorite numbers? Or
但如果我们想要存储一组喜欢的数字呢？或者
maybe we want to store a whole bunch of different people who
我们想存储一大批不同的人物，他们
have different favorite numbers? Well, how do we do that there
都喜欢不同的数字呢？我们该怎么做？有
are several different ways that we can approach this, one of the
几种不同的方式可以解决这个问题。方法之一是
ways we could start approaching this is by creating what's
我们可以创建一个
called a struct of people. Or we create a new type. In our
关于人物的“结构体” (struct)。 或者说，我们在 solidity 中创建一个新的类型。
solidity, we can create a people object that holds both someone's
我们可以创建一个人物对象，其中包含某人的名字
name, and their favorite number. To do that, we say struct
以及他们喜欢的数字。为此我们写下 struct,
people, you went to 56, favorite number, and a string name. Now
People, uint256, favoriteNumber, 以及 string name。现在
we've created a new type called people kinda like you intuited
我们已经创建了一个被称为 People 的新类型，就像 uint256
six, or Boolean, or string. Now we have a people type that we
或 Boolean 或 string。现在就有了一个 People 类型
can use. Now similar to how we created a un 256 public favorite
供我们使用。就像我们创建 uint256 public favoriteNumber 一样，
number, we can do the exact same thing. But with a people, we
我们可以对 People 做相同的事情。
could say people public, we call this person, and we can create a
我们可以写下 People public, 把它命名为 person, 这样我们就创建了一个
new people and assign it to this variable person. So we'll say
新的 People 并将其分配给这个 person 变量。所以就是
equals people public person, equals, and we'll add
People public person 等于，我们要在这里添加
parentheses here to signify we're creating a new person. And
括号，表示我们正在创建一个新的 person。因为
since we made this a struct, we add little curly brackets here
我们把它做成了一个结构体，所以要在这里添加花括号
to let solidity know that we're going to be grabbing from these
才能让 solidity 知道我们要使用的是这些
struct variables, we'll say favorite number is going to be
结构体内的变量，我们接着写下 favoriteNumber，
two, and the name is going to be Patrick semicolon, and then we
是2，以及 name，是 Patrick，别忘了分号。然后我们按下
can hit Ctrl S, or we can go ahead and compile. Now if we go
Ctrl+S，或者我们去点击 Compile 按钮。现在如果我们
ahead and deploy this we now have a new person, since this,
去部署它；我们现在就有了一个新的 person。因为它
again, is a public variable, it has a getter function called
是一个 public 变量，所以它会有一个被称为 person 的 getter 函数。
person. And if we click person, we see our new object, the
如果我们点击 person，可以看到我们的新对象，它的
favorite number is two. And then the name is Patrick, you see
favoriteNumber 是2，以及它的 name 是 Patrick。您可以看到
this zero and this one, because these are showing the index of
这里有一个 0 和 一个 1，它们表示
the different variables. But those of you new to computer
不同变量的索引 (Index)。如果您是刚接触计算机科学的新手，
science, typically in computer science, let's start with the
您需要知道的是，在计算机科学中，计数通常会从数字 0 开始。
number zero. So what are zero with index, we have you in 256,
所以在索引 0 处我们有一个
called favorite number, which is saved at two. And then at index
被称为 favoriteNumber 的 uint256 类型的变量，它保存着数字 2。然后在索引 1 处
one, we have a string, which stands for the name of Patrick,
我们有一个 string 类型的变量 name，它代表 Patrick。
whenever you have a list of variables inside of an object in
每当您往 solidity 的列表变量中放入对象，
solidity, they get automatically indexed. So favorite number gets
它们都会被自动编上索引。所以，favoriteNumber 的
indexed to zero, and name gets indexed to one. Interestingly
索引是 0，name 的索引是 1。有意思的是，
enough, if you have a whole bunch of variables inside your
如果您的合约里有一大堆变量，
contract, like we have public favorite number, this favorite
比如我们有 public favoriteNumber，从技术上来说，
number, actually, technically is getting indexed at the zero with
实际上这个 favoriteNumber 是放到了存储槽 (storage slot) 的索引 0 处。
storage slot. And if we were to make another one of these, maybe
如果我们再做一个，
you want to get six public brother's favorite number, this
比如说 uint256 public brothersFavoriteNumber，
would technically be indexed at the first slot. And then if we
技术上来说，它就是被放到了索引为 1 的槽位上。
were to make one more, maybe sister's favorite number, this
如果我们再多做一个，比如 sistersFavoriteNumber，
would be the next add the second slot. So favorite number at
它就会被添加到索引为 2 的槽位。所以 favoriteNumber 是在 0 处
zero, this add one, and this a two, but we'll learn more about
这个是 1，然后这个是 2。我们会在之后的课程中
that much later in the course. Similarly, favorite number is
再进一步学习这方面的知识。同样，这里的 favoriteNumber 的
index zero name is index at one. Now what we have is great, but
索引是 0，name 的索引是 1。现在我们已经做得很好了，但是
if we want a whole lot of people are we gonna have to keep copy
如果我们想要一大堆 People，难道我们要不停地复制
pasting and changing the people's name person to their
粘贴，然后把人物的变量名变成 person2，
favorite one, number one, number three, will name them ally.
favoriteNumber 是 3，name 是 Ally，
Person three, their favorite number will be seven. Their name
person3，他的 favoriteNumber 是 7，
will be Chad or something. This obviously isn't great way to
name 是 Chad 或者其他什么的。这显然不是个
create lists and large number of people's because we have to
创建大量人物和列表的良好方式，因为我们必须不断
statically keep typing them in. So a much better way to create a
静态地输入它们。所以更好的创建列表的方法是，
list. And let's actually just go ahead and delete Patrick to a
让我们先把 Patrick 和 2 删除掉。
much better way to create a list is to use a data structure
更好的创建列表的方法是使用一种被称为数组 (array)
called an array. An array is a way to store a list, or a
的数据结构。数组是储存列表，或者说
sequence of objects, creating an array works the exact same we've
储存一系列对象的一种方式。创建一个数组的方法和
seen to initialize other different types. Typically, we
初始化其他类型没什么区别。我们通常要做的就是，
do the type of the object, the visibility of the object, and
先声明对象的类型，然后是对象的可见性，
then the variable name. We do the exact same thing with
最后是变量名。我们需要对数组做同样的事情。
arrays. We'll say we want a people array. These little
现在我们想要一个 People 类型的数组，
brackets represent that we want an array of people. We'll give
这个方括号表示我们想要一个包含 People 类型的数组。
it a visibility of public and we'll call it people you could
我们让它的可见性是 public，然后命名为 people。
do the same thing with you and 256 for example, you could say
对于 uint256 来说也是一样的，举个例子，您可以写下
you went to 56
uint256
public favorite numbers list
public favoriteNumbersList
and just add this little array key here. And now favorite
您只需要在这里添加一组方括号，现在 favoriteNumbersList
numbers list is going to be an array or a list We're going to
就是一个数组或者说列表了。我们现在
comment that out for now. Now if I were to go ahead and deploy
先把这里注释掉。现在，如果我要部署这份合约，
this contract, let's go ahead delete the last one, let's
让我们先把之前那个删掉，然后重新部署
redeploy. We now have this blue people button here. Remember,
现在我们就有了一个蓝色的 people 按钮在这里。需要提醒的是，
since it's public, and it's a variable, it automatically is
因为它是 public 变量，所以它会自动获得一个
given a view function, it's given one of these blue buttons.
用于查看它的函数，也就是这个蓝色的按钮。
And instead of just having a single button where the value
并且，现在它不仅仅是一个单独用于显示数值的按钮了，
shows up, it's giving us a form to fill out, it wants to take a
它还有一个可以填写的空格。它需要一个 uint256
un 256 as an input parameter. So if I put zero, I get nothing
作为它的输入参数。现在我输入 0，没什么反应，
back, if I put one, I get nothing back. No matter what you
输入 1 呢，还是没有反应。其实不管您现在往这个格子里输入什么
put in this box, right? Now we're gonna get nothing back.
它都没不会有任何反应。
This is because our people array or our people list is currently
这是因为我们的 people 数组或者说我们的 people 列表，现在还是个空列表。
empty. And the value that it wants is going to be the index
这里的输入值其实是输入
of the object that you want. So for example, if at index zero, I
您想要获得的那个对象的索引。比如说，索引 0 处，
had Patrick, it would show Patrick for zero, if it didn't x
我有 Patrick，就会显示 0 是 Patrick，如果索引 1 处
one I had John, or actually better yet, to Patrick.
我有 Jon，其实可以写的更好一点，2，Patrick
Seven, John,
7，Jon，诸如此类
etc. This is what it would show. But since it's empty, it's going
这样就会显示出结果，不过它现在是空的，
to show nothing. And let's go ahead and remove the public
所以不会显示出任何结果。现在让我们继续并且删除变量
variable from favorite numbers so that we don't get the
favoriteNumber 的 public，
duplicate functions at the moment, we'll just get the
因为我们不需要两个重复功能的函数，
Retrieve function, we'll show you how to add to this array in
我们留下一个 retrieve 函数就够了。接下来我们展示一下如何给这个数组
just a second. This type of array is what's known as a
添加内容。这种类型的数组就是所谓的
dynamic array, because the size of the array isn't given at the
动态数组 (Dynamic Array)，因为我们在初始化这个数组的时候并没有规定
array initialization. If we were to say, a people array and add a
它的大小。如果我们这样写，给这个 People 数组的方括号里
three in these brackets here, that means that this list, or
添加一个数字 3，这就意味着这个 People 列表，或者说数组，
this array of people could only be three people big, if we don't
最多只能放进去三个 People 对象。如果我们不给它设定大小
give it a size, it means it can be any size and the size of the
那就表明它可以是任意大小，并且数组的大小会随着我们添加和减少 People
array can grow and shrink as we add and subtract people, if I
而增大和减小。如果我添加上这个数字 3，
add three, it can only have a maximum of three in the array
那它最多就只能拥有三个对象。
ever, we're going to work with a dynamic array, because we're
这里我们使用动态数组，因为我们希望
going to want to add a arbitrary number of people to this array.
可以添加任意数量的 People 到这个数组中去。
So let's go ahead and create a function that's going to add
所以让我们来创建一个函数，
people who are people array, so we're gonna say function, add
用于往 people 数组中添加 People。我们来写下这个函数，addPerson。
person. And we're going to take string, memory, name as input
我们让它接收 string，memory，_name，作为输入参数。
parameter, and I'll explain that in a minute. And a un 256
我稍后会解释这是什么意思。然后是，uint256，
underscore favorite number, we're going to make this a
下划线，_favoriteNumber，我们让它成为一个 public 函数。
public function, or we're going to do is we're going to call a
我们要做的就是
push function that's available on our people object. So we're
对这个 people 对象调用 push 函数。所以，
gonna say people dot push, and we're going to create a new
我们写下，people，点，push，然后我们要创建一个新的 person，
person, a new people object, which is going to take in the
也就是一个新的 People 对象。它将接收
favorite number.
_favoriteNumber，
And the name.
和 _name
Now, this might be a little bit tricky to you. So let's break
这些东西可能会让人感到有些棘手，所以让我们
this down. People here is capitalized. So we know that
分解一下它们。这里的 People 是大写的，所以我们就能知道，
since capitalize, it's referring to this struct people and not
这个大写的 People 表示的是这个名为 People 的结构体 (struct)，而不是
our variable people, the lowercase people here is
people 变量。这里小写的 people
referring to this lowercase array. So we're saying our array
指的是这个的数组。所以我们写下的就是，我们的数组，点，push，
dot push, or push is the equivalent of adding basically,
push 基本上就是添加的意思。
a new people that grabs favorite number and name. Another way
然后，一个新的 People 获得了 _favoriteNumber 和 _name。
that we could actually do this is we could create a variable of
其实还有一种方式，就是我们先创建一个 People 类型的变量，
type people and then add it like so. So we could say people, new
然后再把它添加进去。所以我们可以这样写，People newPerson，
person equals people. And then we put those brackets the same
等于 People，然后和之前的做法一样把内容放进括号里。
way we did before. You say favorite number is going to be
favoriteNumber 是这个输入值，
this input value, this parameter, and we could say name
或者说参数。然后，name
is going to be this parameter. Now if you hit save, you'll get
是这个参数。如果您试图现在就保存，就会收到这个地方的错误提示，
this error set here, saying data location must be stored in
这里说的是，变量的数据位置必须是 "storage", "memory", 或者 "calldata"，
memory, or called data for variable but no one's given. For
但没有任何一个被给出。
now, we're just going to add the memory keyword here, and I'll
现在我们只需要在此处添加关键字 memory，
explain what it does in a little bit. And then of course, we need
我稍后会解释这是什么意思。然后理所当然地，我们需要把 newPerson
to add the new person into our people dot push right here. So
添加到我们的 people，点，push，这个地方。
this is how we're actually going to push people into our people
所以这就是我们把 People 对象 push 进 people 数组的方法。
array. And I'll get to this memory keyword in a bit. Now if
我稍后会介绍一下这个 memory 关键字是什么意思。
we go back to our deploy tab, we delete our last contract. Let's
现在如果我们回到部署选项，删除之前的合约，然后部署一个新的。
deploy this new one. Right now, if we try to look at the zero
现在，让我们试着查看一下我们的 people 数组的第 0 个 person，
with person in our people array, we get nothing but let's go
我们什么都没得到，不过让我们先添加一个 person。
ahead and add a person, we'll call it, Patrick will be the
我们叫他 Patrick，这就是它的 name，
name, and seven will be the favorite number. So we added
并且 favoriteNumber 是 7，所以我们就添加了
Patrick, we added seven. Now if we look at people's zero, we
Patrick 和 7。现在如果我们查看 people 的 0，我们应该可以看到
should see the zeroeth person has a name of Patrick, and a
第 0 个 person 的 name 是 Patrick，
favorite number of seven, boom. And that's exactly what we do
favoriteNumber 是 7。嘭，这正是我们所看到的
see, we see a favorite number of seven, and we see a string name
我们看到 favoriteNumber 是 7，还看到 string: name 是
Patrick, we tried to add John and do his 16. We hit Add
Patrick，我们再来试试添加 Jon, 16，点击 addPerson，
Person, we can see our transaction go through. And now
可以看到我们的交易通过了。现在，
if we go to people at zero, it's still Patrick with a favorite
如果我们寻找 people 的 0 处，他仍然是 favoriteNumber 为 7 的 Patrick。
number of seven. But if we look at the people at index one, it's
但如果我们查看 people 的索引 1，他就是
going to be John with a favorite number of 16. And if we look at
favoriteNumber 为 16 的 Jon 了。如果我们查看 2，
two, this, of course, should be blank. And we do indeed see
当然就是空白的了。我们也确实看到这里实际上就是
nothing actually happens here. Perfect. Now there's actually a
没有任何事情发生。简直完美！这里其实有几种不同的方式
couple of different ways to create this new person here,
创建 newPerson。
like we showed before, we can use this bracket notation, or
就像我们之前所展示的那样，我们可以使用这个花括号符号，
what we can do is we can actually just add the parameters
或者我们还可以这样做，只是按照它们显示的顺序
in the order that they show. So the first parameter for people
来添加参数。所以，People 的第一个参数
is going to be favorite number. So we can just do favorite
是 favoriteNumber。所以我们可以把 _favoriteNumber 直接放到这里，
number, comma, and the second one is going to be name, the
然后是逗号。第二个参数是 name，
second one is going to be name. So if we save this, this, this
所以第二个位置填上 _name。如果我们保存这个，
line we just created is the exact same as the last line,
这一行和之前写下的那一行是完全相同的。
we're being a little bit less explicit here. So the other way
不过这个写法不太明确，所以通常来说
is generally a little bit better because it's more explicit as to
另一种写法会更好一点，因为那种写法更加明确地表明了
what variables are what or we don't even need to save to this
这些值具体是哪个变量的值。或者我们甚至不需要把它保存到这个变量里，
variable here, we could take out this whole line, replace new
我们可以把这行整个去掉，
person with exactly what we just saw, like so now we don't even
然后把 newPerson 替换成这些，就像这样。现在我们甚至不需要
need the memory keyword. Now, you've probably seen this by
memory 关键字了。